Ian Channing

Senior DevOps / Software Engineer

Website

https://ianchanning.wordpress.com

CONTACT

Email ian@ianchanning.com

Phone +32 491 482 747

Twitter @ianchanning

GitHub ianchanning

SUMMARY

I have 14 years web application development experience across startups, statistical visualization and banking. 5 years ago I moved from London to Belgium and learnt Dutch. I have a long history with building Data Warehouses, porting statistical visualization software and visualizing pipeline corrosion. I am studying Machine Learning and d3.js visualizations in my spare-time.

Languages

English Native speaker

Dutch Working proficiency

WORK EXPERIENCE

SEP 2010 - PRESENT

Senior Developer at Klever:

Designed and developed a CakePHP application with SQL Server for realtime networked sensor measurements. It has an OO JavaScript and Twitter Bootstrap CSS front end. It has scaled from a 3 person university research project to a multi-million pound 30+ person startup company. I've used Selenium testing extensively, which I find the best way to do full system tests, and brought in TDD as the project has matured.

Skills used: WordPress, CakePHP, HTML5, CSS/SASS, JavaScript, Selenium, MySQL, SQL Server, Git, Bash.

Set up a centralised Git auto-deployment to Plesk virtual hosts.

OCT 16 2011 - PRESENT

Open Source Development at GitHub (ianchanning):

Skills used: PHP, Composer, Git.

VandaPHP: A micro PHP framework Composer package.

WP in-sella: WordPress Skeleton for Composer.

APR 2007 - AUG 31 2010

Data analysis and visualization software developer at VSN **International:**

Government funded Data Visualization research project with Leeds University and NAG. Port of a legacy C++ program, merging a forked Linux and Windows C code base and integration of the User Interface with the Java NetBeans Visual Library.

Skills used: PHP, WordPress, MySQL, Java, C.

Converting the company website to WordPress and writing bespoke PHP e-commerce platform.

JULY 2001 - MAR 31 2007

Analyst Developer (Market Risk IT) at Credit Suisse:

Working on three separate successful strategic projects. A 3-tier web application, a C# ad hoc query tool separate and a SQL Server data warehouse.

Skills used: C#, SQL Server, Excel VBA, Data Warehousing.

Volunteer

SEP 2008 - AUG 31 2010

Helper at The Dacorum Sports Club For The Disabled

Weekly helper and coach.

EDUCATION

2015-09-20 TILL 2015-11-29

Stanford University, Coursera (online course)

Machine Learning

GPA - TBC

2004-10-01 TILL 2007-06-30

Birkbeck College, London

Economics, Postgraduate Certificate and MSc (Part-time)

GPA - Merit ~ 3.7

1997-10-01 TILL 2001-06-30

Imperial College, London

Mathematics and Computer Science, MSci

GPA - Upper second ~ 3.5

Awards

CREDIT SUISSE ANNUAL AWARD 2007-07-01

Credit Suisse

London to Paris enduroman charity fund raising in excess of £150,000.

INTERESTS

Cycling / Triathlon, Rowing Coaching, Rowing